<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>Noah&#39;s Webpage</title>
	<link>http://localhost:1313/example/</link>
	<description>Recent content in Examples on Noah&#39;s Webpage</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en-us</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 14:32:51 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/example/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	
	
	<item>
		<title>Valued Long Term Memories</title>
		<link>http://localhost:1313/valued-long-term-memories/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 12:26:35 +1000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>http://localhost:1313/valued-long-term-memories/</guid>
		<description>
&lt;div id=&#34;outline-container-headline-1&#34; class=&#34;outline-2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;headline-1&#34;&gt;
Valued Knowledge and Skills for Long-Term Memory
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;outline-text-headline-1&#34; class=&#34;outline-text-2&#34;&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;outline-container-headline-2&#34; class=&#34;outline-3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;headline-2&#34;&gt;
Purpose of Education
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;outline-text-headline-2&#34; class=&#34;outline-text-3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The selection of what is considered valuable knowledge and skills should be a deliberate process involving discussion and thought, rather than relying on historical precedents. This knowledge should be decided on by society, experts, educators, families, friends, and primarily by the individual student. We should avoid teaching what is irrelevant and inapplicable knowledge.
This decision is crucial because it significantly affects society, friends, family, associates, and ultimately has a profound impact on the student themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;outline-container-headline-3&#34; class=&#34;outline-4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;headline-3&#34;&gt;
What I think is valuable.
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;outline-text-headline-3&#34; class=&#34;outline-text-4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In general, I think the changes we aim to achieve in long-term memory should help individuals lead happy and successful lives while also having the desire and means to contribute positively to the society and world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
The below list details what I think students should know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;outline-container-headline-4&#34; class=&#34;outline-4&#34;&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;headline-4&#34;&gt;
Desired Changes in Long-Term Memory
&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;outline-text-headline-4&#34; class=&#34;outline-text-4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some specific areas of knowledge and skills, that I think students might benefit from:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic Needs: Students are able to obtain food and shelter (often through employment, but not exclusively).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Health Maintenance: Students know how to maintain their mental and physical health (perhaps through knowledge of healthy eating, exercise and the health system).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Resilience: Students are able to create a life that cannot easily disrupted by setbacks (e.g., having insurance if they their home burns in a fire or they are fired at work).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Self-Defence: Students can physically protect themselves from an attack.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Economic Success: Students can secure jobs and earn lots of money.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Status accumulation: Students can gain social status and power.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Societal Systems: Students understand and be able to operate within (e.g., the political, historical, and economic systems of their society).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improving Societal Systems: Students know how to improve societal systems (e.g., through voting, advocacy, and other means).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Community and Collaboration: Students are able to work well with others in their communities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lifelong Learning: Students have a desire and ability to continue learning throughout their lives in order to adapt to new situations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rational Decision-Making and Truth seeking: Students are capable of making rational decisions to ensure a robust quality of life.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meta-cognition: Students are able to think about their thinking, recognise cognitive biases and fallacies, and identify these in themselves.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hedonism: Students know how to have as much fun as possible through learning what they love to do (e.g., dancing, telling jokes, eating, cooking, travelling)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You might disagree with my thoughts above, and I would love to discuss what you think is valuable knowledge?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>There needs to be a Cognitive Model for Activities.</title>
		<link>http://localhost:1313/cognitive-model/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 12:07:36 +1000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>http://localhost:1313/cognitive-model/</guid>
		<description>&lt;p&gt;
The Teacher&amp;#39;s Main Goal is to Change the Student&amp;#39;s Long-Term Memory. To achieve this goal, teachers encourage activities that can facilitate this process, such as recalling information, thinking, writing, discussing, listening, moving, and reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
To improve the likelihood that these activities will effectively change students&amp;#39; long-term memories, it&amp;#39;s important to consider how such memories are formed. Key considerations include: Cognitive Load Theory, the limited capacity for new information, circadian rhythms, sufficient sleep, retrieval practice, interleaving, spaced repetition, deliberate practice, attention span, the impact of stress on learning, proper nutrition, and making learning enjoyable and fun.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
In the article  &lt;a href=&#34;https://andymatuschak.org/books/&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Why Books Don&amp;#39;t Work&amp;#34;&lt;/a&gt;, Andy Matushchak argues that effective learning requires a well-thought-out cognitive model for activities. He contends that traditional methods like reading books or listening to lectures do not align well with how humans form long-term memories. While books may be suitable for certain goals, they are not optimal for memory retention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
From my own experience, the activities that have significantly helped me form long-term memories include incremental reading, spaced repetition, and interleaving, particularly through the use of software applications like SuperMemo and Anki.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>Learning</title>
		<link>http://localhost:1313/learning/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2024 14:41:35 +1000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>http://localhost:1313/learning/</guid>
		<description>
&lt;div id=&#34;outline-container-headline-1&#34; class=&#34;outline-2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;headline-1&#34;&gt;
Learning
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;outline-text-headline-1&#34; class=&#34;outline-text-2&#34;&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;outline-container-headline-2&#34; class=&#34;outline-3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;headline-2&#34;&gt;
Courses Completed
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;outline-text-headline-2&#34; class=&#34;outline-text-3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Completed the following tutorial:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://nextjs.org/learn&#34;&gt;https://nextjs.org/learn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Clojure: The Complete Beginner&amp;#39;s Guide
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.udemy.com/course/clojureprogramming/&#34;&gt;https://www.udemy.com/course/clojureprogramming/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Read majority of the documentation for:
&lt;a href=&#34;https://day8.github.io/re-frame/re-frame/&#34;&gt;https://day8.github.io/re-frame/re-frame/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>Resume</title>
		<link>http://localhost:1313/example/resume/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 May 2024 14:32:51 +1000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>http://localhost:1313/example/resume/</guid>
		<description>
&lt;div id=&#34;outline-container-headline-1&#34; class=&#34;outline-2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;headline-1&#34;&gt;
Noah Johnstone
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;outline-text-headline-1&#34; class=&#34;outline-text-2&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;outline-container-headline-2&#34; class=&#34;outline-3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;headline-2&#34;&gt;
OBJECTIVE
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;outline-text-headline-2&#34; class=&#34;outline-text-3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking to draw together technical, creative, and communicative skills to drive education innovation. Bringing a positive attitude, motivated by humility, clarity, and respect, in all that I do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;outline-container-headline-3&#34; class=&#34;outline-3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;headline-3&#34;&gt;
ATTRIBUTES
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;outline-text-headline-3&#34; class=&#34;outline-text-3&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Growth Mindset&lt;/strong&gt;: committed to ongoing learning from successes and failures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Humility&lt;/strong&gt;: cognisant of the complexity of teaching and software development and open to feedback&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Resilience&lt;/strong&gt;: demonstrated tenacity, patience, and initiative in challenging environments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Analytical&lt;/strong&gt;: striving to incorporate evidence-based practices and engage in regular self-reflection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;outline-container-headline-4&#34; class=&#34;outline-3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;headline-4&#34;&gt;
EDUCATION
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;outline-text-headline-4&#34; class=&#34;outline-text-3&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Masters of Teaching (Secondary) (Leading Learning) Teach For Australia: ACU. 2021-22.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bachelor of Advanced Computing (Honours): ANU. Architecture &amp;amp; Systems Speciality 2016-20.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cambridge ESOL Level* CELTA QCF: RMIT. 2014. Qualified ESL teacher.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bachelor of Arts: University of Melbourne. Linguistics Major + Psych Minor. 2012-15.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CERT IV In Visual Arts &amp;amp; Contemporary Craft, RMIT. 2012.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;outline-container-headline-5&#34; class=&#34;outline-3&#34;&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;headline-5&#34;&gt;
RELEVANT WORK HISTORY
&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;outline-text-headline-5&#34; class=&#34;outline-text-3&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Digital Technology Teacher, Sophia Mundi (VIC), Jan 2024 - Present.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Digital Technology Teacher, Elevation Secondary College (VIC), Jan 2023 – Dec 2023.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Digital Tech, Numeracy &amp;amp; English Teacher, Penguin District School (TAS), Jan 2021 – Dec 2022.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Club Development Officer (ACT), ANU Sport, Mar 2018 – Sep 2020.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Head/Assistant Teacher (ACT), Code Camp, Jan 2018 &amp;amp; 2019.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Client and Project Manager for the ANU Tech-Launcher project (ACT), Feb 2018 – Sep 2019.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delivery Driver (ACT), 2016-2017.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various Hospitality (VIC), 2011-2015.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>Projects</title>
		<link>http://localhost:1313/projects/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 18:15:56 +1000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/</guid>
		<description>
&lt;div id=&#34;outline-container-headline-1&#34; class=&#34;outline-2&#34;&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;headline-1&#34;&gt;
Projects
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div id=&#34;outline-text-headline-1&#34; class=&#34;outline-text-2&#34;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://seatingplanner.noahjohnstone.xyz&#34;&gt;Seating Planner&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://classtimer.noahjohnstone.xyz&#34;&gt;Class Timer&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://tic-tac-toe.noahjohnstone.xyz&#34;&gt;Tic Tac Toe&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	</channel>
</rss>
